A Guide to the RADA--Richmond First Club Archives (1919- )
Virginia Commonwealth University, James Branch Cabell Library
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
Richmond First Club Archives (1919- )
Special Collections and Archives, James Branch Cabell Library, Virginia Commonwealth University
M 238
11.75 linear feet and oversize item
The collection (1919- ) consists of administrative files, correspondence, reports, memoranda, committee files, publications, audio tapes, photographs and clippings pertaining to the Richmond First Club's activities or interests.
Compiled by Betsy Parkin, May 1987
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for use without restrictions
Acquisition Information
Donated to Special Collections and Archives of Virginia Commonwealth University. Accession Numbers: 87-May-22; 87-Jul-36; 88-Jul-16; 89-Nov-40; 90-Feb-10; 90-Mar-17; 90-Apr-26; 90-May-47; 90-May-66; 90-Oct- 144; 90-Oct-145; 90-Oct-146; 95-Oct-40
Biographical/Historical Information
Organized in 1919, the Richmond First Club was founded by Dr. Dice R. Anderson and B. Roy Dudley, Jr. to continue the work begun by the Richmond Civic Association. Strictly non-partisan, closed to employees and officials of the city, the RFC engages in objective studies of the city's government and offers suggestions for improvements. A more specific history can be found in "A Seventy-Five Year Participation in Local Government: Richmond-First Club 1919-1994" by John H. Whaley.
The Presidents of the Club have been: (* denotes deceased)
Jesse F. Wood 1919-1920*
Stuart Ragland 1920-1921*
B. Roy Dudley, Jr. 1921-1922*
Wilmer L. O'Flaherty 1922-1923*
Morton L. Wallerstien 1923-1924*
J. Vaughan Gary* and Robert A. Brock, Jr.* 1924-1925
Kenneth C. Wood 1925-1926*
Irving May 1926-1927*
John F. O'Grady,Jr. 1927-1928*
B. Roy Dudley, Jr. 1928- 1929*
E.L. Williams 1929-1930*
Ernest H. Perkins 1930-1931
Henry S. Raab 1931-1932*
L.C. Bird 1932- 1933*
F. Milton Garey 1933-1934*
J.T. Parkinson, Jr.1934-1935*
Dr. R.B. Pinchbeck 1935-1936*
R. Hugh Rudd 1936-1937*
W. Stirling King 1937-1938
Irving G. Craig* and Dr. Sidney Trattner* 1938-1939
J. Stuart White 1939-1940
William M. Blackwell 1940-1941
Walter Bishop 1941-1942*
Hamilton R. Sutton 1942- 1943
John K. Peeples, Jr. 1943-1944*
John C. MacKinnon 1944-1945
Henry T. Huband 1945-1946*
R.W. Winfree, Jr. 1946-1947
Edward S. Hirschler 1947- 1948
Allen W. Moore and Clifton B. Cosby 1948-1949
Edwin J. Crockin 1949-1950
Roger D. Johnson 1950-1051*
Thomas C. Yeaman 1951-1952
J. Edwin DuPriest 1952- 1953
Leroy E. Marlowe 1953-1954*
Guy T. Mattox 1954-1955*
Hugh R. Thompson, Jr. 1955-1956*
R. Pierce Lumpkin 1956-1957
Edward E. Lane 1957-1958
R. Hugh Rudd, Jr. 1958-1959*
Ben R. Johns, Jr. 1959-1960
Robert P. Buford, Jr. 1960-1961
Irving I. Held, Jr. 1961-1962
E. Ballard Baker 1962-1963
Harry Frazier, III 1963-1964
Edward R. Parker 1964-1965
John F. Kay, Jr. 1965- 1966
Walker Florance 1966-1967
Arthur C. Beck, Jr. 1967-1968
Thomas N. Parker 1968- 1969
Collins Denny III 1969-1970
C. Ray Doggett 1970-1971
Hugh V. White, Jr. 1971-1972
E. Parker Brown 1972-1973
James L. Doherty 1973-1974
William H. Bingham 1974-1975
Charles S. Ylonen 1975-1976
Francis B. Garey 1976-1977
Maxwell G. Cisne 1977-1978
James B. Edge, Jr. 1978-1979
Harry L. Frazier, Jr. 1979-1980
E. Hatcher Crenshaw, Jr. 1980-1981
Gerald P. McCarthy 1981-1982
Hamill D. Jones, Jr. 1982-1983
Kenneth E. Powell 1983-1984
Susan V. Fore Brown 1984- 1985
Robert W. Schaberg 1985-1986
George R. Peterson 1986-1987
Robert R. Laha, Jr. 1987-1988
Wayland W. Rennie 1988-1989
Susan S. Peterson 1989- 1990
Patrick M. McSweeney 1990-1991
Nikki Nicholau 1991-1992;1993;1993-1994
S. Brian Farmer 1994-1995
Peggy Baggett 199
Scope and Content Information
The Richmond First Club Papers consist of administrative files, correspondence, reports, memoranda, committee files, publications, audio tapes, photographs and clippings about the Club's activities or interests. The materials encompass the years 1919-2000, but are concentrated in the period from the mid 1970s through the present. Series VIII contains photocopied material from the Raymond Pinchbeck Papers at the Virginia Baptist Historical Society. The bulk of these materials are dated from the 1950s.
Arrangement
Arrangement
The majority of the files are arranged alphabetically and then chronologically. Bulletins are arranged by date. Duplicates have been weeded from the collection and either returned to the Richmond First Club or disposed of. Photographs, video tapes and audio cassette tapes have been transferred to RG 60, 70 and M 15 respectively. The oversized materials are maps of the Richmond area of the 1980s.
Organization
Series I--Administrative Files (n.d., 1928- ); Series II--Committee Files (n.d., 1958- ); Series III--Committee Reports (1969- ); Series IV--Bulletin (n.d., 1942- ); Series V--Clippings and Miscellaneous Files (n.d., 1963- ); Series VI--Oversize (Located in Map Drawer 26, 1980s); Series VII--RFC 1994 75th Anniversary History; Series VIII--Raymond Pinchbeck Collection of RFC materials (1948-1967).
Other Descriptive Data
Richmond First Club Bulletins
May 19, 1977
June 9, 1977
June 23, 1977
July 14, 1977
September 8, 1977
October 13, 1977
November 10, 1977
December 1, 1977
January 12, 1978 (paper says 1977 but vol.-wise must be 1978)
January 26, 1978
February 9, 1978
February 23, 1978
March 9, 1978 (paper says 1979 but vol.-wise must be 1978)
March 23, 1978
April 6, 1978
May 11, 1978
June 8, 1978
September 27, 1979
October 11, 1979
October 25, 1979
November 8, 1979
November 29, 1979
December 13, 1979
[December, 1979 or January, 1980?]
January 24, 1980
February 14, 1980
February 28, 1980
March 13, 1980
March 27, 1980
April 10, 1980
April 22, 1980
April 24, 1980
May 8, 1980
May 22, 1980
June 5, 1980
September 11, 1980
September 25, 1980
October 9, 1980
October 30, 1980
October 23, 1980
October 30, 1980
November 20, 1980
December 11, 1980
January 8, 1981
January 22, 1981
February 12, 1981
February 26, 1981
March 12, 1981
March 26, 1981
April 27, 1981
May 14, 1981
May 28, 1981
April 9, 1981
March 8, 1984
May 24, 1984
June 14, 1984
September 6, 1984
September 20, 1984
October 11, 1984
October 25, 1984
November 8, 1984
November 29, 1984
December 13, 1984
January 10, 1985
January 24, 1985
February 7, 1985
February 28, 1985
March 11, 1985
March 28, 1985
April 11, 1985
April 25, 1985
May 9, 1985
May 23, 1985
June 6, 1985
(Summer, 1985 Bulletin)
September 12, 1985
September 26, 1985
October 10, 1985
October 24, 1985
November 7, 1985
November 21, 1985
December 12, 1985
January 9, 1986
January 23, 1986
February 13, 1986
February 27, 1986
March 11, 1986
March 27, 1986
April 10, 1986
April 24, 1986
May 8, 1986
May 22, 1986
June 5, 1986
August, 1986
September 11, 1986
September 25, 1986
October 9, 1986
October 23, 1986
November 6, 1986
November 20, 1986
December 11, 1986
January 8, 1987
January 22, 1987
February 12, 1987
February 26, 1987
March 9, 1987
March 26, 1987
April 9, 1987
April 23, 1987
May 7, 1987
May 21, 1987
June 11, 1987
July, 1987
September 14, 1987
September 24, 1987
October 8, 1987
October 22, 1987
November 5, 1987
November 19, 1987
December 3, 1987
December 17, 1987
January 14, 1988
January 28, 1988
February 11, 1988
February 25, 1988
March 10, 1988
March 24, 1988
April 14, 1988
April 28, 1988
May 12, 1988
May 26, 1988
June 9, 1988
September 8, 1988
September 22, 1988
October 20, 1988
November 3, 1988
November 17, 1988
December 1, 1988
December 15, 1988
January 5, 1989
January 19, 1989
February 2, 1989
February 16, 1989
March 2, 1989
March 16, 1989
April 6, 1989
April 20, 1989
May 4, 1989
May 18, 1989
June 1, 1989
August 17, 1989
September 7, 1989
September 21, 1989
October 5, 1989
October 19, 1989
November 2, 1989
November 16, 1989
December 7, 1989
December 21, 1989
January 4, 1990
January 18, 1990
February 1, 1990
February 15, 1990
March 1, 1990
March 15, 1990
April 5, 1990
April 19, 1990
May 3, 1990
May 17, 1990
June 7, 1990
Minutes
August 15, 1977
September 6, 1977
September 20, 1977
October 11, 1977
October 25, 1977
November 8, 1977
November 29, 1977
December 13, 1977
January 24, 1978
February 21, 1978
March 13, 1978
March 21, 1978
April 4, 1978
April 20, 1978
May 9, 1978
June 23, 1979
August 7, 1979
August 30, 1979
September 20, 1979
October 18, 1979
November 1, 1979
November 26, 1979
December 6, 1979
January 3, 1980
February 21, 1980
March 20, 1980
May 1, 1980
May 15, 1980
May 29, 1980
July 24, 1980
September 4, 1980
September 16, 1980
October 2, 1980
October 16, 1980
October 30, 1980
November 18, 1980
December 3, 1980
January 15, 1981
February 19, 1981
March 19, 1981
April 2, 1981
May 20, 1981
July 19, 1984
August 9, 1984
August 23, 1984
September 18, 1984
October 4, 1984
October 18, 1984
November 1, 1984
November 20, 1984
December 6, 1984
January 3, 1985
February 7, 1985
February 21, 1985
March 3, 1985
March 21, 1985
April 4, 1985
April 18, 1985
May 2, 1985
May 16, 1985
May 30, 1985
June 12, 1986
July 10, 1986
July 15, 1986
July 24, 1986
August 7, 1986
August 21, 1986
September 4, 1986
September 18, 1986
October 2, 1986
October 16, 1986
October 30, 1986
November 13, 1986
December 4, 1986
January 5, 1987
January 15, 1987
February 5, 1987
February 19, 1987
April 2, 1987
June 2, 1987
June 13, 1987
June 18, 1987
July 23, 1987
August 6, 1987
August 27, 1987
September 4, 1987
October 1, 1987
October 14, 1987
October 29, 1987
November 12, 1987
November 19, 1987
Contents List
- Administrative Files n.d., 1928-1992
  - Administrative Manual n.d. (Box-folder 1.1)
  - Annual Report 1961-1962 (Box-folder 1.2)
  - Board 1977-1979 (Box-folder 1.3)
  - Board 1978 (Box-folder 1.4)
  - Board 1978-1979 (Box-folder 1.5)
  - Board 1979 (Box-folder 1.6)
  - Board 1985-1986 (Box-folder 2.1)
  - Board 1986-1987 (Box-folder 2.2)
  - Board Meeting Handouts 1987-1989 (Box-folder 2.3)
  - Board Minutes and Annual Reports--Fuhrmann 1965-1967 (Box-folder 2.4)
  - Board Minutes and Annual Reports--Fuhrmann Jan-June 1968; July 1969-April 1972 (Box-folder 2.5)
  - Board Minutes 1977-1978 (Box-folder 2.6)
  - Board Minutes 1979 (Box-folder 2.7)
  - Board Minutes 1980-1981 (Box-folder 2.8)
  - Board Minutes and Annual Reports 1984-1985 (Box-folder 3.1)
  - Board Minutes and Annual Reports 1986-1987 (Box-folder 3.2)
  - Board Minutes 1988 (Box-folder 3.3)
  - Board Minutes 1989 (Box-folder 3.4)
  - Board Minutes 1990 (Box-folder 3.5)
  - Board Minutes 1991 (Box-folder 3.6)
  - Board Minutes 1992-1993 (Box-folder 3A.1)
  - Board Minutes 1993-1994 (Box-folder 3A.2)
  - Board Minutes 1994-1995 (Box-folder 3A.3)
  - Board Minutes 1995-1996 (Box-folder 3A.4)
  - Budget 1968-1970 (Box-folder 3A.5)
  - Budget--General Fund Budget, City of Richmond 1970-1971 (Box-folder 3A.6)
  - Budget 1987-1988 (Box-folder 4.1)
  - Buford, Robert P. 1978-1981, 1983, 1987-1988, 1990 (Box-folder 4.11)
  - Certificates of Recognition 1977, 1979 (Box-folder 4.2)
  - Charter Changes--Fuhrmann 1965-1966 (Box-folder 4.3)
  - Committee Reports (Box-folder 4.31)
  - Committee on Regional Provision of Services Report Dec 1994 (Box-folder 4.32)
  - Committees n.d., 1960, 1978-1985, 1988-1999 (Box-folder 4.4)
  - Constitution and By-Laws (Box-folder 4.5)
  - Constitution, President List, Membership Lists--Fuhrmann 1966, 1968 (Box-folder 4.6)
  - Corporate Papers re: Income and Determination of Tax Exempt Status n.d., 1982 (Box-folder 4.61)
  - Correspondence--Doherty (Box-folder 4.7)
  - Correspondence (Box-folder 4.8)
  - Correspondence 1928 (Box-folder 4.9)
  - Correspondence--Fuhrmann 1941-1943 (Box-folder 4.10)
  - Correspondence--Fuhrmann 1922, 1942-1948, 1954, 1956 (Box-folder 4.11)
  - Correspondence--Fuhrmann 1957, 1961-1962, 1964-1971, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 4.12)
  - Correspondence 1977-1978, 1 of 2 (Box-folder 4.13)
  - Correspondence 1977-1978, 2 of 2 (Box-folder 5.1)
  - Correspondence n.d., 1976-1977, 1979-1980, 1986, 1990 (Box-folder 5.11)
  - Correspondence re: Income and Determination of Tax Exempt Status 1981-1983 (Box-folder 5.12)
  - Federal Aid (Box-folder 5.2)
  - First Vice President 1977-1978 (Box-folder 5.3)
  - Good Government Award 1960 (Box-folder 5.4)
  - Good Government Award 1971 (Box-folder 5.41)
  - Good Government Award 1974 (Box-folder 5.5)
  - Good Government Award 1975 (Box-folder 5.6)
  - Good Government Award 1976 (Box-folder 5.7)
  - Good Government Award 1978 (Box-folder 5.8)
  - Good Government Award 1979 (Box-folder 1979)
  - Good Government Award 1980 (Box-folder 5.10)
  - Good Government Award 1981 (Box-folder 6.1)
  - Good Government Award 1982 (Box-folder 6.2)
  - Good Government Award 1983 (Box-folder 6.3)
  - Good Government Award 1984 (Box-folder 6.4)
  - Good Government Award 1985 (Box-folder 6.5)
  - Good Government Award 1986 (Box-folder 6.6)
  - Good Government Award 1987 (Box-folder 6.7)
  - Good Government Award 1988 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - Good Government Award 1989 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - Good Government Award 1991 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - Good Government Award 1992 (Box-folder 7.4)
  - Good Government Award: Correspondence 1960-1985 (Box-folder 7.5)
  - Good Government Award Correspondence 1977-1979 (Box-folder 7.1)
  - Handbook 1959, 1968, 1971, 1974, 1976-1982 (Box-folder 7.2)
  - Handbook Typescript 1979-1980 (Box-folder 7.3)
  - History (Box-folder 7.4)
  - Luncheons 1989-1990 (Box-folder 7A.1)
  - Meeting (Box-folder 7A.2)
  - Members' Address Changes 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7A.3)
  - Membership; Membership Correspondence 1948, 1954, 1977-1979, 1980, 1986, 1988, 1991 (Box-folder 7A.4)
  - Membership Directories 1984-1986 (Box-folder 7A.5)
  - Membership Directory 1986-1987, 1 of 2 (Box-folder 7A.6)
  - Membership Directory 1986-1987, 2 of 2 (Box-folder 7A.7)
  - Membership Directory 1987-1988 (Box-folder 7A.8)
  - Membership Directory 1988-1989 (Box-folder 8.5)
  - Membership Directory Draft 1985-1986 (Box-folder 8.6)
  - Membership Lists, Mailing Labels--Cain 1985-1987 (Box-folder 8.7)
  - Membership Survey n.d. (Box-folder 8.71)
  - Memoranda, Minutes, Reports--Doherty (Box-folder 8.8)
  - Misc. Memos, Brochures, Correspondence--Cain 1986-1988 (Box-folder 8.9)
  - National Conference for Religious Freedom 1986 (Box-folder 8.91)
  - New Members File--Cain 1987 (Box-folder 8.10)
  - Operating Manual; Master Copy/First Draft (Box-folder 8.11)
  - Past Presidents' Luncheon 1977 (Box-folder 8.12)
  - Photos from Bulletin 1986-1987 (Box-folder 8.13)
  - Planning File 1977-1978, 1 of 3 (Box-folder 9.1)
  - Planning File 1977-1978, 2 of 3 (Box-folder 9.2)
  - Planning File 1977-1978, 3 of 3 (Box-folder 9.3)
  - President--Fuhrmann Aug 1964-Oct 1965 (Box-folder 9.4)
  - President's File--Fuhrmann 1965-1966 (Box-folder 9.5)
  - Proposed name change--Doherty 1973-1974 (Box-folder 9.6)
  - Remarks by Gerald McCarthy (Box-folder 9.7)
  - Second Vice President 1977-1978 (Box-folder 10.1)
  - Secretary 1977-1978 (Box-folder 10.2)
  - Secretary's File--Fuhrmann 1982 (Box-folder 10.3)
  - Secretary's File--Fuhrmann 1983 (Box-folder 10.4)
  - Secretary's File--Begun 1985-1986, 1 of 2 (Box-folder 10.5)
  - Secretary's File--Begun 1985-1986, 2 of 2 (Box-folder 10.6)
  - Secretary's File--Cain 1987 (Box-folder 10.7)
  - Treasurer 1977-1978 (Box-folder 10.8)
  - Treasurer 1978-1979 (Box-folder 10.9)
- Committees n.d., (1958- )
  - Child Care (Box-folder 10.9)
  - Convention and Visitor Bureau Advisory (Box-folder 10.10)
  - Develop Recommendations to Grayson Commission (Box-folder 10.11)
  - Economic Power/Development, Working Papers (Box-folder 10.12)
  - Economic Power/Development, Working Papers (Box-folder 11.1)
  - Economic Power/Development, Working Papers (Box-folder 11.2)
  - Governmental Structures 1985 (Box-folder 11.3)
  - Governmental Structures--Appropriate Size...for...City Council Report 1984 (Box-folder 11.31)
  - Governmental Structures--Clippings n.d., 1964, 1982-1984, 1986 (Box-folder 11.32)
  - Governmental Structures--Correspondence n.d., 1977, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 11.33)
  - Governmental Structures--Reports, Articles, Seminars n.d., 1972, 1975, 1977, 1986 (Box-folder 11.34)
  - James River (Box-folder 11.4)
  - James River Roundtable, Planning File (Box-folder 11.5)
  - James River Roundtable, Working Papers (Box-folder 11.6)
  - James River, Working Papers (Box-folder 11.7)
  - James River, Working Papers (Box-folder 11.8)
  - Jurisdictional Cooperation 1985-1986 (Box-folder 12.1)
  - Jurisdictional Cooperation 1986-1987 (Box-folder 12.2)
  - Jurisdictional Cooperation--Cleveland, Jacksonville, Chicago 1985-1986 (Box-folder 12.3)
  - Jurisdictional Cooperation--Indianapolis 1985-1986 (Box-folder 12.3)
  - Land Use, Working Papers, 1 of 2 (Box-folder 12.5)
  - Land Use, Working Papers, 2 of 2 (Box-folder 12.6)
  - Long-Range Planning (Box-folder 12.7)
  - Metro Chamber Budget Review (Box-folder 13.1)
  - Metropolitan Cooperation (Box-folder 13.2)
  - Neighborhood Uplift Seminar 1979, 1981 (Box-folder 13.21)
  - Regional Cooperation Structure 1989 (Box-folder 13.22)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Chesterfield (Box-folder 13.3)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Chesterfield (Box-folder 13.4)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Chesterfield (Box-folder 13.5)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Chesterfield (Box-folder 13.6)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Goochland (Box-folder 13.7)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Goochland (Box-folder 14.1)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Hanover (Box-folder 14.2)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Hanover (Box-folder 14.3)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Henrico (Box-folder 14.4)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Richmond (Box-folder 14.5)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Richmond (Box-folder 15.1)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Richmond (Box-folder 15.1)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Virginia (Box-folder 15.2)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure--Transportation (Box-folder 15.3)
  - Regional Planning/Cooperation Structure, Working Papers (Box-folder 15.4)
  - Regional Water Authority--Correspondence, Report 1989, 1991 (Box-folder 15.41)
  - Regional Water Issues Committee--Working Papers, Final Report 1989-1990 (Box-folder 15.5)
  - Taxes and Services 1980-1984 (Box-folder 15.6)
  - Taxes and Services, Correspondence (Box-folder 15.7)
  - Trafficways--Fuhrmann 1958, 1960, 1967 (Box-folder 15.8)
  - Urban Renewal (Reports, memos, and other correspondence)--Fuhrmann 1958, 1960 (Box-folder 16.1)
- Committee Reports n.d., (1969- )
  - Air Pollution Control-Fuhrmann 1969 (Box-folder 16.2)
  - Analysis of Costs Related to Service Delivery 1989 (Box-folder 16.3)
  - Annexation Laws--Fuhrmann mid 1960s (Box-folder 16.4)
  - Appropriate Size and Method of Selection for the Chesterfield County Board of Supervisors--Fuhrman 1983 (Box-folder 16.5)
  - Appropriate Size and Method of Selection for the Chesterfield County Board of Supervisors--Fuhrmann 1984 (Box-folder 16.6)
  - Areas of Law Affecting Artists (Box-folder 16.7)
  - Causes of Non-Voting in Municipal Elections--Fuhrmann 1955 (Box-folder 16.8)
  - Charter Changes 1963 (Box-folder 16.9)
  - Committee Reports 1988-1989 (Box-folder 16.10)
  - Comparison of Taxes and Services 1986 (Box-folder 16.11)
  - Report to Determine the Support for changing the Method of Electing the Mayor of the City of Richmond, VA (Box-folder 16.12)
  - Comparison of Taxes and Services 1986 (Box-folder 17.1)
  - Economic Power/Development--Cain 1988 (Box-folder 17.2)
  - Education--Fuhrmann n.d. (Box-folder 17.3)
  - Existing Regional Plans 1989 (Box-folder 17.4)
  - Future of the Capital Area Study Report 1988 (Box-folder 17.41)
  - Governmental Structures in Richmond Metropolitan Area 1986 (Box-folder 17.5)
  - Housing and Urban Renewal--Fuhrmann 1966, 1969 (Box-folder 17.6)
  - Housing Study--Cain 1988 (Box-folder 17.7)
  - James River Round Table--Fuhrmann 1986 (Box-folder 17.8)
  - Jurisdictional Cooperation 1985-1986 (Box-folder 17.9)
  - Land Use Plans 1987 (Box-folder 17.10)
  - Land Use Plans, Typescript (Box-folder 17.11)
  - Long Range Planning--Fuhrmann 1986 (Box-folder 17.12)
  - Mathematics and Science Center 1989 (Box-folder 17.13)
  - Metropolitan Cooperation 1982 (Box-folder 18.1)
  - Metropolitan Cooperation, Typescript (Box-folder 18.2)
  - Metropolitan Police Cooperation--Fuhrmann (1968- ) (Box-folder 18.3)
  - Metropolitan Richmond's James River Corridor 1984 (Box-folder 18.4)
  - Municipal Finance--Fuhrmann 1959 (Box-folder 18.5)
  - Planning and Organization--Fuhrmann 1965 (Box-folder 18.6)
  - Preliminary Committee Reports 1988 (Box-folder 18.7)
  - Preliminary Committee Reports 1988 (Box-folder 18.8)
  - Preliminary Committee Reports 1992 (Box-folder 18.81)
  - Privatization of Government Services in the Richmond Metropolitan Services Area 1994 (Box-folder 18.82)
  - Project on Increasing Intraregional Cooperation with the Richmond Metropolitan Area 1989 (Box-folder 18.9)
  - Regional Plan Survey 1989 (Box-folder 18.10)
  - Regional Planning and Cooperation--Fuhrmann n.d. (Box-folder 18.11)
  - Restoration of Richmond's Canal System--Cain 1988 (Box-folder 18.12)
  - Review of Three Cities 1986 (Box-folder 18.13)
  - Richmond Regional Planning District Commission 1987 (Box-folder 19.1)
  - Schools--Fuhrmann 1956-1962 (Box-folder 19.2)
  - Survey of Business Involvement in the Public Schools 1991 (Box-folder 19.21)
  - Taxes and Services 1985-1986 (Box-folder 19.3)
  - Technical and Vocational Education--Fuhrmann 1964 (Box-folder 19.4)
  - Trafficways 1967 (Box-folder 19.5)
  - Transportation Study--Cain 1988 (Box-folder 19.6)
  - United Health Fund, Report and Correspondence 1959 (Box-folder 19.7)
  - Urban Development Study 1975-1976 (Box-folder 19.71)
  - VCU--Fuhrmann n.d. (Box-folder 19.8)
  - Visions 2020--Future of Central Virginia Project 1986, 1989-1991 (Box-folder 19.81)
  - Visions 2020--Materials and Agenda Oct 23, 1991 (Box-folder 19.82)
  - Voter's Rights--Fuhrmann 1972 (Box-folder 19.9)
  - Ward Representation--Fuhrmann n.d. (Box-folder 19.10)
  - Welfare--Fuhrmann 1974 (Box-folder 19.11)
- Bulletins n.d., (1942- )
  Note: See above for a listing of the Bulletins housed in SC & A. Also, additional Bulletins can be found below in the Raymond Pinchbeck Collection.
  - Bulletin Editor 1977-1978 (Box-folder 19.12)
  - Bulletin, General Information (Box-folder 19.13)
  - Bulletin 1942-1946 (Box-folder 19.14)
  - Bulletin 1947-1951 (Box-folder 20.1)
  - Bulletin 1952-1956 (Box-folder 20.2)
  - Bulletin 1957-1961 (Box-folder 20.3)
  - Bulletin 1962-1966 (Box-folder 20.4)
  - Bulletin 1967-1975 (Box-folder 20.5)
  - Bulletin 1977-1984 (Box-folder 20.6)
  - Bulletin 1985-1986 (Box-folder 21.1)
  - Bulletin 1987 (Box-folder 21.1)
  - Bulletin 1988-1990 (Box-folder 21.3)
  - Bulletin 1991-1992 (Box-folder 21.31)
  - Bulletin 1993-1994 (Box-folder 21.4)
  - Bulletin 1995-1996 (Box-folder 21.5)
- Clippings and Miscellaneous Files n.d., (1963- )
  - Appreciation of City Council Resolution--Doherty 1975 (Box-folder 21.4)
  - Change in City Elections: Voting Rights Act--Doherty 1972-1975 (Box-folder 21.5)
  - Clippings 1967-1988 (Box-folder 21.6)
  - Citizens Committee to Commemorate the Virginia Statute of Religious Freedom 1985 (Box-folder 21.7)
  - City Council--Fuhrmann 1963 (Box-folder 21.8)
  - Critical Commentary from an Interested Party n.d. (Box-folder 22.1)
  - Dissolution of City Charter--Doherty 1973-1974 (Box-folder 22.2)
  - Economic Growth as a Function of Local Government Policy--Fuhrmann 1975 (Box-folder 22.3)
  - Electing Mayors & Council Members at Large 1969, 1984, 1988-1989 (Box-folder 22.31)
  - Emergency Shelter, Inc. (Box-folder 22.4)
  - Future of the Capital Area, v. 1 & 2 (Box-folder 22.5)
  - Governor's Commision: Urban Development Policy--Doherty 1974 (Box-folder 22.6)